Kushal Singh Thakur

https://github.com/Kush026 Mobile: +91 9498073574

Summary

Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in developing a large and complex web application. Ability to automate tasks and troubleshoot problems. Developed applications from ground zero and was involved in all phases of the development.

EXPERTISE

Web Development Object-oriented Programming
Design Patterns Test-driven Development

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras

Chennai, India

B. Tech in Aerospace and M. Tech in Applied Mechanics

July 2011 - April 2016

Email: singhkushal937@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

FP Tech Science Pvt. Ltd.

Bengaluru, India

Software Development Engineer

Dec 2017 - Present

- Search Application: Designed and built multiple features in search applications such as RESTful API to search based on different filters, implemented various types of facets and dynamic price range facet.
- Category Hierarchies: Developed an application solely which is responsible for storing, retrieving and manipulating category hierarchy data and metadata.
- Auto-suggest: Redesigned the application to make it multi-lingual.

Tech: Java, Spring, Spring boot, Hibernate, JUnit, Mockito, MySQL, Apache Solr, Maven, Gradle

ZenParent Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Bengaluru, India

Software Developer

July 2016 - Oct 2017

- User Generated Content: Created a service which allows users to submit articles on the site which can be reviewed and approved manually or published automatically after a stipulated time interval.
- Website Revamp: Revamped website and was solely responsible for Backend development.
- Automation: Implemented an algorithm to generate personalized newsletters and email notifications. I also designed a report generating system which was responsible for collecting article performance parameters from google analytics.
- Apache Solr: Integrated Apache Solr with Wordpress to speed up the content search across the website.
- Troubleshooting & Performance: Troubleshoot the site performance issues using New Relic. Found critical issues on site which were degrading site performance and user traffic.
- AMP pages: Designed Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMPs) to enhance mobile user experience.

Tech: WordPress, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Apache Solr, HTML, CSS, AJAX, JSON, Git, JQuery

Technical Skills

Programming/Scripting: Java, JavaScript, Python, PHP, SQL.

Web: Spring, Spring Boot, REST, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, AJAX, JSON

Data Stores: MySQL, Apache Solr

Miscellaneous: Git, Junit, Maven, Gradle, Linux, Unix

Projects

- Boggle Word Game: Designed Boggle word game in Java language.
- **Seam-carving**: Seam-carving is a content-aware image resizing technique where the image is reduced in size by one pixel of height (or width) at a time.